Finding Aid for the Davida Rochlin Papers LSC.2369
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: The American porch, 1976-1994; 1976-1986
  - Subseries 3.3: Porch book and publications, 1983-1994
    - Porch calendar, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Porches, Decks & Outbuildings, Fine Homebuilding book featuring an essay on the American porch by Davida Rochlin, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Fine Homebuilding Magazine (October/November 1985, no. 29) (Box 36, Folder 6)
- Series 4: Davida Rochlin Architecture (DRAIA) work, 1980-2019
  This series contains work completed by Davida Rochlin Architecture (DRAIA) with materials beginning in 1980. It includes drawings, plans, reports, photographs and correspondence. Major projects covered include the Four Porch House (also referred to at 3251 Selby), Honakai House (also referred to as the Thomas/Goff Residence), Sea Level House (also referred to as West Sea Level), Elijah Wood Residence, Market Street Residences, Kenquest Corporate Headquarters, and Rancho Girasol.
  The series is organized by project and chronologically. Most projects are organized chronologically. The following projects have more significant documentation surrounding them and are, therefore, organized in subseries by project, also in chronological order: Thomas/Goff Residence, Elijah Wood Residence, Sea Level House, and Market Street Residences.
  - Subseries 4.1: Davida Rochlin Architecture (DRAIA) projects, 1980-2010
    This subseries includes projects completed by DRAIA between 1980 and 2010. This subseries excludes projects that have more comprehensive documentation. Materials in this subseries include photographs, negatives, slides, hand drawings and plans, and digital materials.
    The subseries begins with an assortment of project photographs organized alphabetically by project. The rest of the subseries is arranged chronologically. Additional project photographs and oversize hand drawings are found at the end of the subseries.
    - Project photographs, circa 1980-2010 (Box 5)
      Photographs organized alphabetically as follows: Balian Kitchen, Bruin Kids Architecture, Klapper, Marcus (3251 Selby) Before/After, Meehan/Kotler, Northridge Pediatric Clinic, ORR, J/G Rochlin Porch, Romero Residence, Schwartz Residence, Stein, Stern Sunset Boulevard.
    - Resumé, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Lucien Ruby residence, Telluride, Colorado, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Study model, circa 1980-2010 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 42 Malibu Colony residence, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Steinbaum before and after photographs, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Schwartz residence additions and alterations, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mattson project before photographs, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Camino Llanoso front porch after photographs, circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Early Years School, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Chancellor Gregory photographs, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Chancellor Gregory notes and plans, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Orr residence, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Rancho Girasol project description and plans, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Rancho Girasol photographs and slides, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Fountain Valley floor plan, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Cigna/Colton floor plan, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Cigna prototypical casework, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Outline of standards development for all DRAIA Cigna projects and renderings of standardized cabinets.
    - Cigna Montclair floor plan, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Kenquest before photograph, circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kenquest project description and floor plans, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Kenquest model photographs and drawings, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Kenquest slides and photographs, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Cal State Los Angeles Engineering and Technology Building space planning and furniture specifications, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Trestor/Pushkin residence floor plans, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby plans, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby photographs and slides, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby permits (general), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby permits (structural and energy), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby permits (developer fee rebate), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby (Title 24 and HVAC), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby (demolition permit), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Landscape design concepts etc. 3251 Selby, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Landscape design concepts etc. 3251 Selby (deck), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby: letter to the editor of Sunset Magazine, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Innes-Brisbin Residence renovation after photographs, circa 2001 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Balian before and after photographs, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Baker residence, 2002-2003 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      This folder contains 4 3.5 inch floppy disks.
    - Milazzo residence, 2002-2004 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      This folder contains 1 CD.
    - Leo Baeck Temple, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Weintraub project binder, 2007-2008 (Box 14, Folder 9-10)
    - Weintraub correspondence and contracts, 2007-2008 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Weintraub drawings, 2007-2009 (Box 39, Box 14, Folder 12)
      This folder contains 5 CDs.
    - Calvert project binder, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Calvert schematics, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      This folder contains 2 CDs.
    - Kotler project, circa 1980-2010 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Cigna photographs, circa 1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Rancho Girasol (Taos) photographs, circa 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Four Porch House/3251 Selby photographs, circa 1999 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Kenquest photographs, circa 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Kenquest before photographs, circa 1995 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Kenquest model photographs, circa 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Kenquest drawing photographs, circa 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Kenquest photographs, circa 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Cal State Los Angeles School of Engineering computer laboratory: space planning photographs, circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Leo Baeck before photographs, circa 1999 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Kenquest building oversize photographs, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Oversize hand drawings for Drummond and Balian projects, 1999, 2001 (Box 28)
    - Oversize hand drawings for Kenquest Building, 1995 (Box 29, Box 30)
    - Project presentation boards for Kenquest and Net Zero Canyon Orchard Residence, 1995, 2010 (Box 38)
  - Subseries 4.2: Thomas/Goff Residence (Honakai House), 2001-2004
    This subseries contains materials related to DRAIA work on the Thomas/Goff Residence (also referred to as the Honakai House) in Big Island, Hawaii, completed in 2003. Materials include photographs, site plans and renderings, documentation of specifications, permits, and requirements, and records of correspondence, contracts, and design review submissions.
    - Thomas/Goff Residence site photograph, circa 2003 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence specifications for Homeowners' Association, 2002-2004 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence city building requirements, circa 2001-2004 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence meeting notes, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence notes, contracts, and correspondence, 2002-2004 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence plans and meeting notes, 2002-2003 (Box 40)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence project binder, 2002-2004 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence design notes and correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence interior materials, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence design review submittal, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 6, Box 40)
    - Specifications for Thomas/Goff Residence, circa 2001-2004 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence drawings and photographs, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence final design review submittal, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Spiral-bound design review submission for exterior specifications for phase II of the project. This folder also includes a list of project consultants, an application for construction of improvements, and loose site plans and elevations.
    - Thomas/Goff Residence construction schedules, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Specifications for the Thomas/Goff Residence, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Thomas/Goff design submittal, specifications, and building permit, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - Thomas/Goff Residence completed house photographs, circa 2004 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Large mounted photograph of Thomas/Goff Residence, Honakai House, circa 2003 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Oversize drawings and plans for Thomas/Goff Residence, 2001-2003 (Box 31)
    - Project presentation boards, 2004 (Box 38)
  - Subseries 4.3: Elijah Wood Residence, 1999-2000
    This subseries contains materials related to the DRAIA design for Elijah Wood's residence in Santa Monica, California. Materials include plans, drawings, photographs, correspondence, documentation about materials and fixtures, and notes.
    - Elijah Wood Residence Title 24 report and structural documents, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Elijah Wood Residence drawings, 2000 (Box 41)
    - Elijah Wood Residence project binder, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 8, Box 17, Folder 1, Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Elijah Wood Residence photographs, circa 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.4: Sea Level House, 2003-2008
    This subseries contains materials related to the design and construction of the Sea Level House (also often referred to as West Sea Level) in Malibu, California between 2003 and 2008. Materials include "before" photographs, large site plans, drawings, official documents, correspondence, notes, reports, permit applications, and hearing appeals. Much of the documentation covers structural and environmental considerations unique to the site and city requirements. This includes hydrology studies, solar energy, structural engineering and calculations, soil reports, archaeological and biological assessment, and geotechnical reports. There are also approvals for city planning and planning commission hearings, septic, fire planning, civil and structural codes, such as grading, drainage, and erosion control, and the homeowners' association. Documentation includes construction observation, process for obtaining the foundation permit, cost estimates, Title 24, and Environmental Review Board (ERB) as well.
    - Sea Level House site photographs "before", circa 2003-2008 (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
    - West Sea Level plans, correspondence, and contracts, 2005-2006 (Box 17, Folder 4, Box 42)
      In addition to correspondence, contracts, and invoices concerning the project on topics including geologic investigation, engineering deign, wastewater treatment, ando ownership transfer, this file includes architectural and site plans on these issues.
    - West Sea Level plans, 2005-2006 (Box 42)
    - West Sea Level hydrology report, 2005-2006 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - West Sea Level storypoling, 2005-2006 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - West Sea Level solar energy records, 2004-2006 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - West Sea Level assessor maps, circa 2003-2008 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - West Sea Level fuel modification planning, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - West Sea Level structural calculations, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - West Sea Level correspondence, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - West Sea Level soil report, 2002-2006 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Also includes historic reports from 1989.
    - Sea Level House project binder, 2005-2006 (Box 18, Folder 9, Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Plans submitted to Huckabee and Environmental Review Board (ERB), 2005 (Box 48)
    - City of Malibu approvals for Sea Level House, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence 31894 Sea Level, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 31894 Sea Level plan check corrections architectural/structural, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Construction observation 31894 Sea Level, 2005-2007 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Sea Level House obtaining foundation permit, issued 11-1-06, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - West Sea Level engineering cost estimates, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - West Sea Level staff report, planning commission, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - West Sea Level Malibu Planning Commission hearing, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - West Sea Level structural engineering, 2005-2006 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - West Sea Level response to Coastal Commission appeal, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - West Sea Level building department submittal, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - West Sea Level Marny Randall Landscape contract, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Malibu Encinal Homeowners Association (MEHOA) homeowner architectural review application and Coastal Development permit submittal revisions, 2005-2006 (Box 20, Folder 8, Box 43)
    - West Sea Level drainage, grading, and erosion control plans, 2005-2006 (Box 20, Folder 9, Box 44)
      Includes updated and incomplete/superseded versions from October 2005.
    - West Sea Level Rincon biological assessment, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - West Sea Level surveyor information, 2004-2005 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - West Sea Level septic documentation, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - West Sea Level schematic septic plan, 2004-2005 (Box 45)
    - West Sea Level private road deed, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - West Sea Level Title 24 report, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - West Sea Level approved coastal development permit submittal and landscape, fuel modification and vegetation management plan, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 15, Box 45)
    - West Sea Level landscaping design, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 16, Box 45)
    - West Sea Level Malibu biology report, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - West Sea Level landscape, fuel modification, and vegetation management plans and approvals and fire safety, 2004-2006 (Box 21, Folder 2, Box 46)
      This folder includes correspondence with the City of Malibu assigning address to the property and plot maps. This folder also contains large plans for landscape, fuel modification, and vegetation management, including approvals.
    - West Sea Level coastal community hearing, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - West Sea Level commission agenda report, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - West Sea Level surveys, circa 2003-2008 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - West Sea Level Malibu environmental reporting, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - 31894 Sea Level planning approval for plan check, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - West Sea Level correspondence/reporting, 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - West Sea Level geological and geotechnical review, 2004-2006 (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
    - West Sea Level soil and hydrology studies, 2004-2006 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - West Sea Level soil gradation test, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - West Sea Level wastewater impact study, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - West Sea Level waste reduction and recycling plan forms, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - West Sea Level survey reports, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - West Sea Level wastewater treatment system construction specifications and plans, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - West Sea Level fuel modification plan, 2005-2006 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - West Sea Level landscape, fuel modification, and vegetation management plans and approvals, 2005 (Box 46)
    - West Sea Level storm water pollution prevention plan, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - West Sea Level permits, 2006-2007 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - West Sea Level revised planner drawings, 2004 (Box 47)
    - West Sea Level revised planner drawings, 2005 (Box 47)
    - West Sea Level coastal development permit applications, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - West Sea Level Environmental Review Board (ERB) CD-ROM submittal, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - West Sea Level set back requirements drawing and floor plans, 2005 (Box 46)
    - West Sea Level title insurance and deed, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - West Sea Level archaeology report, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - West Sea Level hydrology and stormwater requirements, circa 2003-2008 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.5: Market Street Residences, 2014-2015
    This subseries contains materials related to the Market Street Residences at 3198 Market Street in San Francisco, California, designed by DRAIA. Materials include site photographs, building concepts, elevations, floor plans, area survey, site and building plans, sections, and renderings. Additional materials include Green Building Permit materials.
    - Market Street Residences drawings, renderings, coverage, site survey, and plans, 2014-2015 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Market Street Residences building concept, site photographs, site plan, floor plans, sections and elevations, and area surveys and plans, 2014-2015 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Market Street Residences yard plan and site survey/study, 2014-2015 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Market Street Residences green building permits, site plans and sections, and photographs, 2014-2015 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Market Street Residences floor plan and elevations, 2014-2015 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Market Street Residences site and floor plans and elevations, 2014-2015 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Market Street Residences complete set of drawings and plans, 2015 (Box 49)
- Series 5: Davida Rochlin Architecture (DRAIA) office records, 1983-2017
  This series contains materials related to the DRAIA office including general office records, brochures, and requests for proposals (RPFs), and publications about DRAIA projects or written by Rochlin.
  - Suberies 5.1: General office records, 1984-2017
    This subseries includes office materials and records for DRAIA from 1984 to 2017. Materials include correspondence, resumés, certifications and licenses, employee and intern records, and templates for company forms and stationery.
    - Correspondence from Mary Jo Reid, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      One letter from Mary Jo Reid to Rochlin regarding the office in the Barry Building.
    - Resumés, circa 1984-2017 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - American Institute of Architects (AIA) certificates, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Includes certificates from the national and Los Angeles chapters.
    - Santa Monica College architecture talks, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Women Owned Business certification, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Women Owned Business certification, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Women Owned Business certification, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Women Owned Business certification, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Women Owned Business certification, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Hawaii American Institute of Architects (AIA) license and application materials, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - California architecture license forms, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Prospectus prep for art gallery, 2008-2009 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Hours logs, 1998-2010 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Employee and intern records, 2001-2011 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - San Vicente office lease, 2007 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - LEED Certifications, 2009-2011 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Architecture licenses, 1989-2017 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - American Institute of Architects (AIA) Archipages company profile, 2004-2010 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Barry building, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Photograph of old office, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Company forms and stationary, circa 1984-2017 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Business licenses, 1992-2000 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Los Angeles Center for Enriched Studies certificate of participation in annual career day program, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1992-2003 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Suite 215 office layouts, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - UCLA course: architecture workshops for children, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - LEED certifications, 2012-2015 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - LEED Gold certification, 2012 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 5.2: Brochures and requests for proposals (RFPs), 1990-2010
    This subseries contains brochures, statements of qualifications, and RFPs sent out from DRAIA to various institutions including UCLA, Los Angeles Department of Parks and Recreation, and Kaiser Permanente. Other materials include contest and award submissions to Metropolitan Home, American Institute of Architects (AIA), and Warner Brothers Minority Owned Business/Women Owned Business Program.
    - Example medical brochure, circa 1990-2010 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Kenquest materials for 1996 American Institute of Architects Los Angeles (AIA/LA) design awards submission, 1996-1997 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Rochlin/Marcus Residence (3251 Selby) materials for Metropolitan Home, Home of the Year Contest submission, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Rochlin/Marcus residence/3251 Selby is also often referred to as the Four Porch House.
    - West Sea Level materials for American Institute of Architects National Housing Award submission, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - West Sea Level materials for 2010 American Institute of Architects Los Angeles (AIA/LA) Design Awards program (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) laboratory renovation project submission, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Warner Brothers Minority Owned Business/Women Owned Business Participation Program submission, 1992-1996 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Los Angeles Department of Parks and Recreation statement of interest and qualifications, 1994-1999 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Collected submissions and request for proposal responses, 1990-1999 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Beverly Hills statement of qualifications, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Kaiser Permanente statement of qualifications, 1994-1995 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - University of California, Irvine statement of qualifications, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Malibu City Hall request for proposals and statement of qualifications, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - West Sea Level and Crossroads School for Arts and Sciences statements of qualifications, circa 1990-2010 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Suberies 5.3: Press and publications, 1983-2017
    This subseries contains DRAIA correspondence and writing for publications including Sunset Magazine, Greenopia, Designer's West, View Magazine, Metropolitan Home Magazine, and Martha Stewart Magazine.
    - Redken Research Center Designers West article, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Sunset Magazine correspondence, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Sunset Magazine submission, 2001-2004 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Submitted to Coldwell Banker Previews, 2017 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Greenopia "The Urban Dweller's Guide to Green Living Los Angeles" books, 2006-2008 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Designer's West Magazine vol. 31/no. 2, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - View magazine, 2015-2017 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Metropolitan Home magazine, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Martha Stewart magazine, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Series 6: The New American Porch pop-up show, 2010
  This series contains materials related to Rochlin's 2010 exhibition, The New American Porch. Materials include an exhibition slideshow, exhibition materials, such as the artist statement and wall signage, publicity for the show, and photographs and slides from the exhibition. Media included contain the slideshow and other digital exhibition materials.
  - Slideshow draft and final (digital file), circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    This folder includes 3 CDs labeled "American Porch Slide Show Final - Powerpoint final American Porches 8-4-10," "American Porch 7-29-10 slide show," and "American Porch slide show final: 8-4-2010."